<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>A Place for Asides - Nonfiction</title><link href="http://tonyromarock.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://tonyromarock.github.io/feeds/nonfiction.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://tonyromarock.github.io/</id><updated>2020-04-12T23:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Saving His Life by Lee Sandlin</title><link href="http://tonyromarock.github.io/saving-his-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-12T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-12T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Peter Mortimer</name></author><id>tag:tonyromarock.github.io,2020-04-12:/saving-his-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Rereading the story of Lee Sandlin's father-in-law.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have become aware of Lee Sandlin when reading his essay &lt;a href="http://leesandlin.com/articles/LosingTheWar.htm"&gt;Losing The War&lt;/a&gt;, which was featured in Ira Glass' anthology &lt;em&gt;The New Kings of Nonfiction&lt;/em&gt;. This led me looking for more articles by Lee Sandlin. Many of his popular articles are freely available on his personal page and that is where I found his essay &lt;a href="http://www.leesandlin.com/articles/SavingHisLife.htm"&gt;Saving His Life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Saving His Life&lt;/em&gt; Lee Sandlin chronicles the life of his father-in-law Nick Cherniavsky. The story of how Nick ended up in the US is very interesting. Nick lived in different Russian communities in Asia and eventually arrived the USA as a refugee. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His memoirs show the interesting history many cities in Asia share being a meeting point for many ehnic groups. These melting pots often caused by the large refugee movements due to the many wars for territory in the first half of the 20th century and the expansive colonialism by the global powers starting already in earlier centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also a story about a time where, from our perpsective, these seemingly large and well-remembered events happened, but for people back then these news are often learned about in very unusual ways. It is interesting to see how these global events are interwoven into Nick's life in many different ways. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also converted the story to the .epub format, so that someone interested in reading &lt;em&gt;Saving His Life&lt;/em&gt; can comfortably read it on their eBook reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tonyromarock.github.io/extra/ebooks/Saving_His_Life.epub"&gt;Download Lee Sandlin's &lt;em&gt;Saving His Life&lt;/em&gt; for your eBook reader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy this article as much as I did. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="nonfiction"></category><category term="essays"></category></entry></feed>